<lecture title="Inspections &amp; Design Review: Carcassonne (1)">

Formal inspections of design documents and code emerged in the 1970s as an
important technique for discovering flaws in software. A driving person
behind the movement was Michael Fagan at IBM. Many people have since
investigated the effectiveness of the technique and its variations. In this
course, we follow the now well-established format as much as possible,
except that we also use the inspections to learn how to construct
software. 

<h3>Inspections</h3>

<p>People identify two different types of inspections: one concerning
  design documents (e.g., requirements, specifications, documentations)
  and the other one concerning programs.</p>

<p>In both cases, an inspection proceeds in at least three phases:
  preparation, the actual inspection followed by feedback, and a follow-up
  meeting. In a business context, you need to <em>prepare</em> for an
  inspection. You have your own work to do, and you don't know what others
  are doing. In this course, you have solved a similar problem or written a
  similar document. So you know what is going on.
</p>

<p>The actual inspection is an presentation of the code to a team
  of readers. The goal of the presentation is to uncover
  mistakes and to point out omissions. The panel may engage in a dialog
  but only as long as they are trying to confirm a problem. Once the
  problem is confirmed they stop and move on. 
</p>

<p>At the end, the "coder" receives a list of feedback points. Someone is
  put in charge to follow up on this list. A follow-up session may
  involved another presentation. </p>

<p>Studies have found that the effectiveness of reviews directly depends
  on the size of the team. Two readers in addition to the coder are much
  less effective than three readers. Ideally, these three readers assume
  the role of a moderator, who leads and directs the presentation; a second
  reader, and a secretary who takes notes for the feedback report. </p>

<p>The degree preparation of preparation also plays a role in the
  effectiveness of code walks but to a much smaller degree than the number
  of people. For more information, see the papers in the bibliography. </p>

<h3>Bibliography</h3>

The literature on the inspection of software artifacts is huge. Here are
some early, historical entry points. If you need to have more recent
evidence that it works, conduct a literature search before you present
those papers alone to your manager. 

<li>Fagan. Design and code inspections to reduce errors in program
  development. IBM Syst. J. 3. 1976</li>

<li>Fagan. Advances in software inspection. IEEE ToSE 12(7). 1986</li>

<li>Russel. Experience with inspection in ultralarge-scale
  developments. IEEE Software. Jan 1991.</li>

<li>Weller. Lessons from three years of inspection data. IEEE Software. Sep
  1993.</li>

<li>NASA. Software Formal Inspections Guidebook.</li>

<hr />

<p><b>Presenters:</b> 
BinH T Le, Juan Flores
</p>

<p><b>Readers:</b> 
Martin Fowler (moderator), 
Zach Joress (secretary), 
Chris Barthle (second reader)
</p>

<hr />
<p><b>Presenters:</b> 
John Vulner,
Daniel Suchy
</p>

<p><b>Readers:</b> 
Andreas Tejeda (moderator), 
John Sullivan (secretary),
Eric Bloomquist (second reader)
</p>

</lecture>
