<week>
<assignment due="1/21 @ noon">

<p><b>Objective:</b> to work in pairs on use cases and stories</p>

<hr /> 

<p><b>Task 1:</b> Your task is to synthesize your efforts from the previous
  week. Compare your analyses, your data descriptions, and your uses
  cases. Then jointly produce a draft. Designated one person as the primary
  author; the other partner should edit the draft alone. Switch
  roles. [POINTS: 3]
</p>

<hr />

<p><b>The Story, Amended:</b> Check your analyses and use cases in light of
  the following three questions: 
<ol>
<li>What happens if your system's computer goes down during the afternoon?
  Assume someone knows how to re-start it later. </li>

<li>What happens if your system's input or output files get corrupted?
  Assume someone edits them by hand before, while, or after your program
  runs.</li>

<li>How does your system interact with the office's billing system?</li>
</ol>
 Determine whether these scenarios require revisions of your existing use
 cases or whether they require entirely new use cases. 
</p>

<p><b>Task 2:</b> Your second task is to consider what changes when you
  consider the amended story. [POINTS: 2]
</p>

<hr />

<p><b>Task 3:</b> Your third task is to analyze the story of Carcassonne
  and to write up the use cases for this project. Complete tasks 1 and 2
  first and use what you learned about working out uses cases for this last
  task. [POINTS: 5]
</p>

<hr />

<p><b>Product:</b> Turn in a tar bundle with three subdirectories labeled
  1, 2, and 3. The first one (1) should contain the result and intermediate
  products for task 1. Specifically it should contain a plain text file
  called <code>final.txt</code> and the earlier drafts labeled
  <code>1.txt</code>, <code>2.txt</code>, etc. The second directory (2)
  should contain the result of task 2. The third directory (3) should
  contain a file for the concept graph (as a jpeg) and one file per use
  case of task 3. You may use any of your favorite drawing tools to draw a
  concept graph. If you have access to a professional programming
  environment, you may use its tools, too, but don't think it will impress
  us. 
</p>

</assignment>
</week>
