<div>

<scheme>(red-title "The Game")</scheme>

<p>
Carcassonne is a tile-laying game. The objective of the game is to build regions
and to occupy regions. When a region is completed, the players with the most
followers in the region receive an appropriate number of points. The game is
over when there are no more tiles available. The player with the most points
wins.</p>

<p>Note: This version of Carcassonne is mostly simpler than the original
but has been changed at a few points to drive home some points on the
interaction among software components. You may want to consult the rules
for the original game and even play it to get a feeling for the process but
beware that the rules differ.</p>

<scheme>(generalp "The Tiles")</scheme>

Every tile depicts some theme: an abbey, a castle, a road, or a combination of
these. Here are three examples: 
<blockquote>
<img src="Tiles/0tile00.jpg" /> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;
<img src="Tiles/0tile1.jpg" />  &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;
<img src="Tiles/tile11.jpg" />  &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;
</blockquote>

The leftmost tile with the red boundary is the unique starter tile. At the
northern end it depicts a fragment of a castle, the white line running from left
to right is a road fragment. The center tile is an abbey. The rightmost tile
depicts the fragment of a castle that borders the northern as well as the
eastern side of the tile. 

<p>Before you read on, take a look at <a href="tiles.html">the
collection of all tiles.</a> </p>

<scheme>(generalp "Turns, Part I")</scheme>

At each turn, a player obtains a tile at random from a heap of tiles that
are arranged face-down, turns it over, and adds it at some matching place
to the map. Matching means that the border of each neighboring tile is the
same as the border of the newly placed tile. Furthermore, the newly placed
tile <em>must</em> share a border with at least one existing tile. To
create a match, a player may rotate a tile by 90, 180, or 270 degrees.

<p>Placing a tile may thus involve
<ol>
 <li>one neighboring tile: 
  <table border="0">
   <tr><td>&nbsp;</td><td>0</td><td>1</td></tr>
   <tr><td>0</td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile00.jpg" /></td></tr>
   <tr><td>1</td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile1.jpg" /></td></tr>
   </table>

   Here the player placed tile 1 without rotating it to the south of the starter
   tile, matching grass to grass.  </li>

 <li>two neighboring tiles: 
  <table border="0">
   <tr><td>&nbsp;</td><td>-1</td><td>0</td></tr>
   <tr><td>0</td><td><img src="Tiles/270tile2.jpg" /></td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile00.jpg" /></td></tr>
   <tr><td>1</td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile1.jpg" /></td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile1.jpg" /></td></tr>
   </table>

   This time the player rotated tile 2 by 270 degrees into the (-1,0)
   spot. On its eastern border the tile matches two roads (with grass); on
   the southern border it matches grass.</li>

 <li>three neighboring tiles: </li>
  <table border="0">
   <tr><td>&nbsp;</td><td>-1</td><td>0</td></tr>
   <tr><td>-1</td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile1.jpg" /></td><td><img src="Tiles/90tile4.jpg" /></td></tr>
   <tr><td> 0</td><td><img src="Tiles/270tile2.jpg" /></td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile00.jpg" /></td></tr>
   <tr><td> 1</td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile1.jpg" /></td><td><img src="Tiles/0tile1.jpg" /></td></tr>
   </table>
 
   If the player places the tile into spot (-1,0) in this situation, the turn
   requires three matches for the tile: on its southern, eastern, and northern
   border. 
 <li>or even four neighbors. Make an example where placing a tile requires four
   matches. 
 </li>
</ol>
</p>

<p>Over the course of a game, this map of tiles evolves. The map is usually not
densely connected, like the four examples might suggest. The ultimate shape
depends on the strategy of the players and how they operate to build regions.</p>
 
<p>Note: If it is impossible to add a tile to the map, the player may return the
tile to the heap and pick up another tile.</p>

<scheme>(generalp "Regions")</scheme>

A region is a collection of connected tiles with the same theme (roads, castles)
or an abbey with its surrounding neighbors. A region is complete if it meets the
following conditions: 

<ul>
<li>A road is complete if it has an end piece at either end. End pieces are:
farms; forks in the road; and castles and abbeys:
<blockquote>
2: <img src="Tiles/0tile2.jpg" /> &nbsp; &nbsp;
6: <img src="Tiles/0tile6.jpg" /> &nbsp; &nbsp;
7: <img src="Tiles/0tile7.jpg" /> &nbsp; &nbsp;
19: <img src="Tiles/0tile19.jpg" /> &nbsp; &nbsp;
23: <img src="Tiles/0tile23.jpg" /> &nbsp; &nbsp;
24: <img src="Tiles/0tile24.jpg" /> &nbsp; &nbsp;
</blockquote>

<p>Example: <blockquote><img src="Tiles/comp-road0.jpg" /></blockquote></p>

</li>

<li>An abbey is complete if it is surrounded by eight (8) pieces.

<p>Example: <blockquote><img src="Tiles/comp-abbey1.jpg" /></blockquote></p>
</li>

<li>A castle is complete if it its walls form a continuous line.

<p>Example: <blockquote><img src="Tiles/comp-castle1.jpg" /></blockquote></p>
</li> 

</ul>

<scheme>(generalp "Turns, Part II")</scheme>

After placing a piece, a player may also place a follower on a region if the
region is incomplete and if no other follower already occupies the
region. Placing a follower is optional and should follow strategic
considerations because a player has only seven followers. 

<p>When the placement of a tile completes a region, the follower(s) are
immediately returned to their respective player. This implies that the player
who just placed the tile may use a returned follower to end his turn.</p>

<p>It is permissible to connect two distinct regions with followers, and this
kind of move is indeed an important part of the game.</p>

<scheme>(generalp "Scoring")</scheme>

Players receive points when regions are completed. If a region is populated by
the followers of several players, the player with the most followers in the
region receives the points. Sometimes several players have the same number of
followers in the region. In this case all players with the highest number of
followers receive the points. 

<p>Points correspond to the number of pieces in a region. Thus a completed abbey
always yields nine (9) points. A completed road produces as many points as there
are participating tiles, including the end pieces. Each castle tile accounts for
two (2) points, unless it also contains a flag, in which case it accounts for
four (4) points. </p>

<scheme>(generalp "The End")</scheme>

A game consists of 70 to 75 turns, depending on the number of players. That is,
there are 70 to 75 cards (1 through 24) in the heap. You may assume that the
chances of picking any one of the 24 cards are the same. 

<p>At the end of the game, players receive additional points for followers
that occupy abbeys. The score for an incomplete abbey region consists of
one point for the abbey tile plus the number of tiles that touch the
abbey, i.e., a player may obtain up to eight (8) points for an abbey at the
end of the game. The followers on incomplete roads and incomplete castles
are ignored.</p>

<scheme>(generalp "Bibliography")</scheme>

Dan Becker, <a href="http://www.io.com/~beckerdo/games/reviews/CarcassonneReview.html">Carcassonne</a>, Game Review.

</div>
