<div>

  <p>The goal is to assign approximately one project per week. The projects
  will include writing assignments, modifications of Java programs,
  designing and implementing a project from scratch, and
  maintaining/modifying code. Like in the real world, the project
  descriptions will become available only a short time (typically a week or
  so) before they are due. This simulates the time pressure you will
  experience in industry. As you rush to complete your projects, don't
  forget, however, that looking ahead often makes life much easier in the
  long run than doing short-term tasks only. 
  </p>

  <p>The main project of the course is to implement the board game
  <em>Carcassonne</em>. For your orientation, a description of the game is
  available through the tabs on the left. 
  </p>

<scheme>(generalp "Pair Programming")</scheme>

<p>You must work on (almost) all projects in pairs. <font color="red">Pair
  programming means that you do all things together.</font> You may switch
  partners only after a consultation with the course staff.
</p>

<p>Start searching for a partner now. You must submit your partner's name
  to Sam T-H. by <font color="red">on Friday January 14</font>. Use the
  format of a project title page to do so. In return, you will be granted
  access to the submission server. 
</p>

<scheme>(generalp "Submission")</scheme>

<p>You will submit your projects by the specified time in two pieces. For
  every project you will turn in a cover page in the first class following
  the due date. The cover page contains these pieces:
  the project title, 
  the date, 
  the names of the partners, 
  the signatures of the two partners, 
  the list of points you chose not to pursue.
 The signatures guarantee that you completed the task without any outside
 assistance. 
</p>

<p>For every project, you will also email a tar bundle to Sam T-H. before the
due time. The bundle must contain

<ol>
<li>a README file with instructions for
       compiling,
       linking,
       executing,
       running the test suite.
 your code on the department's Windows or Unix boxes. Following these
 pieces the file may contain additional documentation. 
</li> 

<li>all header and code files needed to test and to run the program</li>
</ol>
Sam will not accept any emails that arrive with a time stamp after the due time,
but will save them instead for documentation of tardiness. 
</p>

</div>
