<div time="1174952901">

On Mar 26, 2007, at 7:33 PM, someone wrote:

<blockquote>
<p>
1. Are there any restrictions to what our player implementations are
allowed to know about the game? I know the specified interfaces are
intentionally limited but shouldn't our players be able to know things like
scores, size of other player's hands, and any card that is discarded to the
Stack? More specifically, can they keep track of anything that they would
be able to if the game was played in real life?  
</p>

<p><font color="red">
These sound like great suggestions for future extensions. For now, your
player should know what it can find out through the functions/methods in
the given interface. For everything else, you would need more guarantees.
</font></p>

<p>
2. Related to 1, can our player keep track of every card placed on the
discard stack? Once again, this is limited by the interface but it's
something that could conceivably happen in real life.
</p>

<p><font color="red">
Since the player can inspect the entire stack during a turn, the answer is
yes. Can it see cards that are played and disappear between turn n and turn
n+1? No. 
</font></p>

<p>
3. What happens when a player requests to register in the middle of the game? 
</p>

<p><font color="red">
Impossible. 
</font></p>

<p>
Are they queued for a turn (and dealt a fresh 7 once they're reached) or
are they forced to wait for the next battle before entering? I could make
arguments for either approach. 
</p>

<p><font color="red">
No.
</font></p>

<p>
4. When a player is caught cheating what happens to their hand? Placed
aside before the nextBattle/newDeck? 
</p>

<p><font color="red">
Their hand is ignored. But again, this sounds like a great idea for a future change request. 
</font></p>

On Mar 26, 2007, at 6:24 PM, someone else wrote:

<p>
 For task 3, you want the optimal strategy, is this for a human player,
 knowing everything ... or ... is it for a squadron scramble computer
 player, where all they know about is ...
</p>

<p><font color="red"> 
This should be "describe your best strategy" meaning the automated player
that does best in your tournaments. Keep in mind that the interfaces are
given. You may not assume any additional knowledge on the side of the
player. 
</font></p>

</blockquote>
Just in case: my answers are in red. 

</div>
