<div time="1171399277">

<p>
 <font color="red">Read <a href="Blog/670-submission-notes.html">Richard's
 turn-in guidelines.</a> Now. Or else. </font>
</p>

<hr />

Also, concerning project 6, he adds: 
<ul>
  <li>
    <p>
      The test cases that you write should be placed in
      <code>Tests/Project6</code>; the <code>Tests</code> directory should
      be at top-level within your submission directory.  (That is,
      <code>Tests</code> should be a sibling of <code>README</code>.)
    </p>

    <p>
      Each test case should be stored in a separate file, with the
      <code>.xml</code> extension, and a filename that suggests the purpose
      of the test case.  <strong>DO NOT PUT SPACES IN THE TEST CASE
      FILENAMES.</strong>
    </p>

    <p>
      You may put other files in this directory (e.g., notes to yourself
      about the test cases), but they must not have <code>.xml</code>
      extensions.
    </p>
  </li>

  <li>
    <p>
      For task 1, you must include a <code>run-harness</code> script that
      will start your test harness (<em>not</em> your test-case
      administrator).  This script is subject to the same requirements as
      your other scripts.  Further, it must expect <em>no</em> command-line
      arguments (optional arguments for your own purposes are fine), and it
      must perform no input-output beyond that specified by the project.
    </p>

    <p>
      This script should run a single test case, which it reads from stdin,
      write the test's output to stdout, and then terminate.
    </p>

    <p>
      In most cases, this script will simply start your test harness.
      (Since a Unix child process, by default, inherit its parent's open
      file descriptors, your test harness will have the same stdin/stdout
      as the script.)
    </p>
  </li>

  <li>
    <p>
      If you attempt Task 2, your <code>run</code> script must accept one
      command-line parameter, the name of the test case to run.  (You may
      support additional parameters if you desire, as long as they are not
      required.)
    </p>
  </li>
</ul>
</div>
