<div time="1169590285">
<b>SVN Project Structure:</b>

<p>
 If we specify a directory name or filename in the SVN repository, your
 turnin tree must match that name *exactly* -- including case and
 punctuation.
</p>

<p>
  In the notes for lecture 3, we stated that each project statement would
  contain the name of the directory that you are to create within the
  <code>turnin</code> directory.  For simplicity, we will simply use the
  pattern established by the previous assignment: <code>Project2</code>,
  <code>Project3</code>, <code>Project4</code>, and so on.
</p>

<p>
  For project 3 and forwards, your <code>README</code> file and the
  required scripts (<code>compile</code>, etc.) must appear at top-level
  within the project directory.  You may structure your code any way you
  like within the project directory, but your <code>README</code> file must
  contain a roadmap, as discussed in lecture 3.  So, if you choose to use
  Java, you may create the directory structure corresponding to your code's
  packages.
</p>

<p>
  Any memos should appear within a <code>Memos/Project<i>N</i></code>
  directory.  The <code>Memos</code> directory must appear at top-level
  within the main project directory.  (Rationale: we specify that the
  project name must appear twice within the path so that you can keep all
  of the memos you write to us in your <code>work</code> directory, and
  keep them well-organized, and we can find the memos easily when we
  grade.)
</p>

<p>
  Finally: In lecture 3, we asked that your <code>README</code> file
  include a list of which parts you attempted.  Since this is information
  is to be included on the cover page that you submit, you do not need to
  include this in your <code>README</code>.
</p>

<p>
  To summarize:
<pre>
<code>
  ProjectN
   |
   +---- Memos
   |     |
   |     +---- ProjectN
   |            |
   |            +---- memos here as necessary
   |
   +---- README
   +---- compile
   +---- run
   +---- run-tests
   +---- code, in subdirectories as appropriate.
</code>
</pre>
</p>
</div>
