<week>
<assignment due="3/23 : NOON" points="??/???">

<!-- center><font size="+4" color="red">Draft</font></center -->

<h3>Running a Turn, Enforcing the Rules of the Game</h3>

PROBLEM: a player may wish to discard a squadron with aircraft (A,1) plus
 two wildcards even though some other player has already discarded (A,2)
 (A,3) plus a wildcard as a squadron. This is not allowed. BUT players
 don't know what others have discarded, so how can they check? 

Project 12? 

<p>The goal of this Project is to implement a rule checker for Squadron
 Scramble. The rule checker is called by <code>play-one-turn</code>. It
 consumes a player's representation and the result of playing one turn. It
 determines whether the actions during the turn and the results of the turn
 are consistent with the rules of the game.
</p>

<p>
<font color="red">
Your rule checker is <em>not</em> to enforce the rule that a player cannot
discard/attack with a squadron if the same airplane type has been used to
form a squadron before. Since the player doesn't receive all the necessary
information, it is unfair to enforce the rule. 
</font>
A player shouldn't use the same aircraft in two separate turns with
different wildcards for this purpose, and the player does have enough
information to play by this portion of the rule. For simplicity though, we
ignore this part, too. 
</p>

<p><b>Task 1:</b> [POINTS: 10] Design the rule checking function.</p>

<pre>
<code>
<font size="-1">
SEQUENCE DIAGRAM

               TESTER      
                |
&lt; - I/O : 1 --->| 
                |  create()
           pp = |-----------------------------------> ProxyPlayer 
                |                                         |
                |           first-hand(hand)              |
                |---------------------------------------->|
                |                                         |
                |                                         |
                |  create / run-one-turn()                |
                |----------> Administrator                |
                |              |                          |
                |              | create()                 |
                |          t = |----------> Turn          |
                |              |              |           |
                |              |------------------------->|  take-turn(t)
                |              |              |           |  
                |              |              |           | &lt; --- I/O : 2 --->
                |              |              |           |  
                |              |              |&lt;----------| get-a-card-from-deck() 
                |              |              |&lt;----------| get-cards-from-stack(n)
                |              |              |           |  
                |              |&lt;=========================| done 
                |              |              |        ======
                |              |              |        ======
                               |------------->|             end()
                               |            =====
                               |            =====
&lt; - I/O : 3 --->|
  
                
I/O 1: TESTER reads an _xtrn_ <em>and</em> a _hand_ with all the necessary items
       for the Administrator from standard input. 
I/O 2: ProxyPlayer reads as many _mesg_ from standard input as there are
       and then one _done_. 
       The _mesg_s are turned into appropriate method calls. After
       it reads _done_, the ProxyPlayer finishes its turn and returns the
       specified information to <code>play-one-turn</code>. 
I/O 3: TESTER writes one of the following to standard output and then
       closes the port: 
       -- a CONTRACT _resp_, if a <a href="contracts.html">contract</a> is violated;
       -- a TIMING _resp_, if a <a href="contracts.html">timing contract</a> is violated;
       -- a CHEATING _resp_, if a rule of the game is violated;
       -- or the following five XML elements if the turn worked out okay: 
         bool  %% is this the end of the battle?
         borc  %% the return card (or false)
         slst  %% the discards 
         from  %% did the player take the cards from the stack or the deck?
         atta  %% (possibly empty) series of attacks
</font></code></pre>
For your convenience, the message formats and the formats of test cases are
collected <a href="MESSAGES4.txt">in one file (MESSAGES4).</a>

<p><b>Task 2:</b> [POINTS: 10-50] The above diagram modifies the
 interaction protocol of Projects 6 and 7 so that your test harness first
 calls the proxy-players's <code>first-hand</code> method (basically a
 non-empty list of cards) and then plays one turn.</p>

<p>
 Modify your test harness so that it plays according to the above protocol.
</p>

<p>
 Also develop a test suite for your rule checker according to the
 specifications. As for Projects 7 and 9 we will run all test cases against
 all revisions of <code>play-one-turn</code>. For each of your tests that
 discovers an error in some other rule checker, you will get an extra
 point. If two (or more) of your test cases discover the same flaw, you
 will receive <em>one</em> extra credit point, not two. You may receive at
 most 40 extra credit points this way. 
</p>

<p><b>Task 3:</b> [POINTS: 5] Your third task is to design and implement a
 test case administrator. It reads a test case, starts up your test
 harness, and writes XML messages to standard output and listens for
 transmissions on standard input. It compares the received input against
 the specified output and decides whether <code>play-one-turn</code>
 passed.
</p>


</assignment>
</week>

