<week>
<assignment due="3/30 : NOON" points="??/???">

<!-- center><font size="+4" color="red">Draft</font></center -->

<h3>Implement the Game Administrator, Groom Good Players</h3>

<p>
 The goal of this Project is to of the game administrator so that you can
 conduct Squadron Scramble tournaments. For projects 9 and 10 you have
 implemented some essential building blocks. So the purpose of this project
 is really just to finish what you have started. 
</p>

<p>
 Initially you should use two to six instances of your Project 6 player for
 the tournaments. Once you can run tournaments you can use the framework to
 develop and implement alternative player strategies. (We may run a
 class-wide tournament with the best player from each team.) 
</p>

<p><b>Task 1:</b> [POINTS: 30] Implement the game administrator. It must
 conduct complete games according to the rules of Squadron Scramble. That
 is, it must run battles until (at least) one player has more than 250
 points. For each battle, the administrator creates a new deck, shuffles
 it, hands out first hands to all registered players, creates a one-card
 stack, and finally starts the battle. At the end of a battle, it scores
 all players and adds/subtracts the points of the battle to the point total
 for each player.
</p>

<p>
 You are free to design the game administrator and its interface. You must
 ensure, however, that it can deal with an arbitrary number of
 players. These players can register with the administrator when it is
 created or afterwards.
</p>

<p>The task includes the addition of a callback protocol that informs
 players of the loss of a discarded bomber squadron. That is, when player
 1 performs an attack with a fighter squadron on some bomber squadron of
 player 2, the administrator must inform player 2 of this attack. The
 new player method has this signature: 
<pre><code>
   player-inform       : player/c discard-bomber/c -> any
   ;; inform player that the squadron was shot down 
</code></pre>
</p>

<p>
 Make sure that your administrator deals with failing and cheating players
 in an appropriate manner. That is, if a player diverges, crashes, violates
 the contracts of a turn, cheats, your administrator must ignore the turn
 and throw the player out of the game.
</p>

<p><b>Task 2:</b> [POINTS: 15] Your second task is to design and implement
 alternative strategies for playing the game. Think of at least three
 different strategies and implement them in players. Then run some games to
 find out which of the strategies performs best.
</p>

<p><b>Task 3:</b> [POINTS: 5] Describe the best strategy in a short,
 two-paragraph memo (at most 400 words). </p>

</assignment>
</week>

