<week>
<assignment due="1/26 : NOON" points="11/31">

<h3>Representing Basic Data</h3>

<p>
 The first task is always to design a data representation for the basic
 pieces of information. To do so, you study the use cases and develop
 interfaces for these first. If the problem is complex, you may wish to use
 role-playing to check whether implementations of the interfaces
 suffice. My own inclination is to prepare interfaces and classes for
 modifications later and to modify them as needed. 
</p>

<p><b>Task 1:</b> [POINTS: 4] The representation of cards suggests the
  following hierarchy of data and functions:
<pre>
<font size="-1">
<code>
                       +-----------------+                
                       | Card            |
                       +-----------------+                
                       | Image file_name |  
                       +-----------------+                
                                |                   
                               / \                  
                               ---                  
                                |                   
                    ---------------------           
                    |                   |           
               +----------+    +-----------------+  
               | WildCard |    | Aircraft        |  
               +----------+    +-----------------+  
               +----------+    | String name     |  
                     |         | Alliance a      |  
                    / \        | Category forb   |  
                    ---        +-----------------+  
                     |         +-----------------+  
         ---------------------           
         |                   |           
  +--------------+     +--------------+
  | Victory      |     | Keepem       |
  +--------------+     +--------------+
  +--------------+     | int index    |
  +--------------+     +--------------+
                       +--------------+
</code>
</font>
</pre>
 Use classes or modules (or some other grouping mechanism in your chosen
 language) to represent this form of data.</p>

<p>
 You may wish to consider adding the following functions:
 <code>card-value</code>, <code>card-&lt;</code>,
 <code>cards-have-same-name</code>. [POINT 1]
</p>

<p><b>Task 2:</b> [POINTS: 4] Your second task is to write up three use
  cases: 
<ol>
<li>"Players register with administrator"</li>
<li>"Player takes turn"</li>
<li>"Administrator plays a complete game"</li>
</ol>
 Note that the third case uses the second one. </p>

<p><b>Task 3:</b> [POINTS: 3] One goal of writing up use cases (or
  "stories") is to find out whether some (possibly important) piece of
  information is missing. Often you meet your customer only for scheduled
  meetings and to prepare these meetings you write down questions. Your
  task is to formulate <em>three questions</em> concerning Squadron
  Scramble. The questions must be about the game per se, not its
  implementation, because you are still working out the problem (not its
  solution). 
 </p>

</assignment>
</week>
