<week>
<assignment due="3/2 : 11:59pm" points="40/250">

<h3>Visualize the State of a Player</h3>

<p><b>Task 1:</b> [POINTS: 30] Your last task before spring break is to add
 a module that helps you visualize a game graphically. First, change the
 interface of player so that create-player consumes a second argument:
<code>
<pre>
   create-player :: string? boolean? -> player/c
   ;; create a player, with[out] visual display
</pre>
</code>
 If the argument is <code>true</code>, the player's actions are
 visualized. If the argument is false, they aren't. 
</p>

<p>
 To accomplish this, you should use the model-view pattern (aka MVC). That
 is, your visualization code should be completely separated from your
 player code. Furthermore, it should be possible to use two distinct,
 unrelated graphical tool boxes to implement the visualization
 module. [Note: the pattern usually comes with the word "control". Since
 you are not implementing an interactive graphical user interface, you
 don't need a control.]
</p>

<center><img src="8.png" width="300"></img></center>

<p>Your code should be able to display at least fours parts of the player's
  state:
<ol>
<li>the name of the player (as specified in <code>create-player</code>);</li>
<li>the current hand;</li>
<li>all discarded airplanes, which includes both the properly discarded
  squadrons as well as those fighter squadrons used to shoot down the
  bomber squadrons of other players; and </li>
<li>the number of points that the player is guaranteed to win during the
  on-going battle, i.e., the points for the bomber squadrons that have been
  shot down. 
</li>
</ol>
 This part of the assignment is worth 10 points.
</p>

<p>Your code should be able to visualize at least two player actions: 
<ol>
<li>each change to its state during a method call,</li>
<li>and the beginning of a turn.</li>
</ol>
Each of those two pieces is worth 10 points. 
</p>

<p>
 The external design (i.e., the look and feel) of the graphical
 visualization is up to you. You are free to choose your favorite graphical
 toolbox and display medium. I have posted an example above, but you are
 not forced to follow this in any way.
</p>

<p>
 For the internal design, you should follow the standard rules of
 programming you have encountered at Northeastern. 
</p>

<p><b>Task 2:</b> [POINTS: 10] Read up on the Open Cable Application
 Platform (OCAP). Then write up one paragraph (at most 250 words, usual
 HTML format) comparing the 670 project to elements of OCAP programming.
</p>
</assignment>
</week>
