<week>
<assignment due="3/16 : NOON" points="??/???">

<!-- center><font size="+4" color="red">Draft</font></center -->

<h3>Running a Turn, Enforcing Contracts</h3>

<p><b>Task 1:</b> [POINTS: 20] Your first task is to equip your
  implementations of <code>turn</code> and <code>play-one-turn</code> with
  behavioral and temporal contracts as described in the
  <a href="contracts.html">Contracts Specifications</a>. The goal of these
  contracts is to prevent ill-behaved players from crashing the server or
  from upsetting its basic internal invariants. </p>

<p>You may either implement the contracts manually or through the use of a
  contract system for your language. A contract error must signal an
  exception from which the overall program may recover. Note: you are
  better off learning how to use a contract system than writing your
  own. As far as I know, all chosen languages provide some basic contract
  system though none of them provide sound ones. 
</p>

<p><b>Task 2:</b> [POINTS: 20] Your second task is to equip your test
  harness of <a href="7.xml">Project 7</a> with capabilities for checking
  test cases concerning contract violations. That is, if the (proxy-)player
  violates the contract with <code>turn</code> or
  <code>play-one-round</code>, the test harness must report the violation
  on stdout.  See <a href="MESSAGES3.txt">MESSAGE3.txt</a> for the revised
  and extended language of test cases. </p>

<pre>
<code>
<font size="-1">
SEQUENCE DIAGRAM

               TESTER      
                |
&lt; - I/O : 1 --->| 
                |  create()
           pp = |-----------------------------------> ProxyPlayer 
                |                                         |
                |                                         |
                |  create / run-one-turn()                |
                |----------> Administrator                |
                |              |                          |
                |              | create()                 |
                |          t = |----------> Turn          |
                |              |              |           |
                |              |------------------------->|  take-turn(t)
                |              |              |           |  
                |              |              |           | &lt; --- I/O : 2 --->
                |              |              |           |  
                |              |              |&lt;----------| get-a-card-from-deck() 
                |              |              |&lt;----------| get-cards-from-stack(n)
                |              |              |           |  
                |              |&lt;=========================| done 
                |              |              |        ======
                |              |              |        ======
                               |------------->|             end()
                               |            =====
                               |            =====
&lt; - I/O : 3 --->|
  
                
I/O 1: TESTER reads a _xtrn_ with all the necessary items
       for the Administrator from standard input. 
I/O 2: ProxyPlayer reads as many _mesg_ from standard input as there are
       and then one _done_. 
       The _mesg_s are turned into appropriate method calls. After
       it reads _done_, the ProxyPlayer finishes its turn and returns the
       specified information. 
I/O 3: TESTER writes either a CONTRACT _resp_, a TIMING _resp_, or 
         bool  %% is this the end of the battle?
         borc  %% the return card (or false)
         slst  %% the discards 
         from  %% did the player take the cards from the stack or the deck?
         atta  %% (possibly empty) series of attacks
       to standard output, then closes the port.

The formats of the external representations is a minor revision of the
<a href="MESSAGES3.txt">old XML data definitions</a>, including <a href="MESSAGES2.txt">MESSAGES2</a>. 

For your convenience, they are collected in one file: <a href="MESSAGES3.txt">MESSAGES3</a>.
</font>
</code>
</pre>

<p><b>Task 3:</b> [POINTS: 0, see below] The third task is to develop test
 cases for your administrator that ensure that it can deal with
 <code>esac</code>-type test cases as before and that is also deals with
 <code>CONTRACT</code> and <code>TIMING</code> errors properly. 
</p>

<p>
 POINTS: The base score for Task 2 is 0 points.  We will run our own test
 administrator for <em>all test harnesses</em> on our test cases. We will
 also run <em>all submitted test cases</em> on our test harness. 
</p>

<p>
 (1) You will receive a point for each test case that discovers
 an error in our interaction module. If distinct test cases discover the
 same error in someone else's code, you don't get more than one point.  (2)
 You will lose one point for each test case that contains an error. (3) You
 will not receive fewer than 0 points (though we will display the negative
 points in the chart).
</p>

<p><b>Task 4:</b> [POINTS: 5] When the game administrator hands a turn to a
  player, the latter should protect its integrity with contracts about the
  cards that it may receive information about through the turn. Formulate
  such contracts in plain English and explain how we can get some of the
  necessary information already and what we would need to add to get the
  rest.  See EXERCISE in <a href="contracts.html">Contracts
  Specifications</a>.
</p>

</assignment>
</week>
