<div>

<scheme>(red-title "The Game")</scheme>

<p>
 Squadron Scramble is a card game from the World War II era. <em>Restoration
 Hardware</em> resurrected the game a couple of years ago, which is where I
 bought it for my sons.
</p>

<p>
 The objective of the game is to conduct an "air war" with the Axis and
 Allies fighters and bombers depicted on the playing card. Naturally, each
 "war" consists of "battles." A player earns points in each battle until some
 player has won the "war." 
</p>

<p>
 Note: I modified the rules of the game a bit for this course. My purpose is
 to drive home some points concerning interactions among software
 components. You may want to consult the rules for the original game and even
 play it to get a feeling for the process but keep in mind that the rules
 differ.
</p>

<scheme>(red-title "The Cards")</scheme>

<p>
 The deck includes airplane types from all major Axis and Allies
 nations [see "Aircrafts" tab on the left], e.g., 

<blockquote>
<table align="center">
<tr>
<td align="center" valign="bottom">
 <img src="SquadronScramble/Northrop A-17a.jpg" width="50" alt="[a17]" />
</td>
<td align="center" valign="bottom">
 <img src="SquadronScramble/Dornier Do 26.jpg" width="50" alt="[do26]" />
</td>
<td align="center" valign="bottom">
 <img src="SquadronScramble/Mitsubishi 96.jpg" width="50" alt="[p47]" />
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">Northrop A-17a (US)</td>
<td align="center">Do 26 (German)</td>
<td align="center">Mitsubishi 96 (Japan)</td>
</tr>
</table>
</blockquote>
 There are three cards for each airplane type in the deck. 
</p>

<p>
 In addition to airplane cards, the deck contains one "Victory" card and
 six "Keep'em Flying" cards: 
<blockquote>
<table align="center">
<tr>
<td align="center">
 <img src="SquadronScramble/victory.jpg" width="50" alt="[Victory Card]" />
</td>
<td width="200" />
<td align="center">
 <img src="SquadronScramble/keepem.jpg" width="50" alt="[Kee'em Flying Card]" />
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">Victory Card</td>
<td width="200" />
<td align="center">Keep'em Flying Card</td>
</tr>
</table>
</blockquote>
 All seven of them may be used as wild cards. 
</p>

<scheme>(red-title "How to Conduct a Battle")</scheme>

<p> 
 At the beginning of a <font color="purple">battle</font>, the dealer
 shuffles, the deck and then hands each player seven cards. The rest of the
 deck is placed faced-down. The top-most card is turned over (face-up),
 visible to all.
</p>

<p>
 A randomly chosen player starts the battle. The remaining player get turns
 in a clock-wise fashion. 
</p>

<p>
 When it is a player's turn, the player must take exactly one card from the
 face-down deck or at least one card from the face-up
 <font color="purple">stack</font>. At the end of the turn, the player must
 return one card, face-up to the top of the face-up deck, unless the player
 has put <em>all</em> cards on his hand on the table and has thus finished
 the battle.
</p>

<scheme>(question "What happens when the deck or discard pile runs out during play?"
"The \"return one card\" rule implies that there is always at least one card
 on the stack. It is possible, however, that the deck is exhausted after
 some number of turns. In this case, your game administrator will turn the
 discard stack into a deck, shuffle it, and use the top-most card as the new
 stack. Question: is it still possible for a battle to run forever? Is this
 question decidable? [What does this mean?]")
</scheme>

<p>
 A squadron consists of three cards for the same airplane type or two cards
 for the same type plus one wild card <font color="purple">or of one
 aircraft card plus two wild cards.</font> If a player has
 <font color="purple">complete squadrons</font> on his hand, he may put
 <font color="purple">them all down</font> (face-up).
 <font color="purple">As the player discards squadrons, he may use a
 complete Axis [Allies] squadron of fighters to shoot down exactly one
 Allies [Axis] squadron of bombers that some other player has already put
 on the table.</font> The cards become his and can't change owner anymore.
</p>

<p>
 When a player has put down all cards in his possession, the battle is
 over. <font color="red">A battle is also over if the deck is empty and
 there are fewer than three cards left on the stack.</font>
</p>

<scheme>(red-title "Scoring a Battle, ...")</scheme>

<p>
 When a battle has ended, each player receives fifteen (15) points for a
 fighter squadron on the table and thirty (30) points for a bomber squadron,
 including those shot down from other players. Every player must then 
 subtract five points (5) per fighter card and ten (10) points per bomber
 card on his hand. <font color="purple">The wild cards on a player's hand
 cause no penalty.</font> 
</p>

<scheme>
 (question "Can a player have a negative score?" "Yes.")
</scheme>

<scheme>(red-title "..., Winning a War")</scheme>

<scheme>
 (question "How many players may participate? When may they start participation?"
 "
 For a physical game, the rules recommend two to six players. For a virtual
 game, you shouldn't set such arbitrary limits. [Or should you?] Naturally,
 once a game has started, no additional players may join.")
</scheme>

<p>
 The war is over when at least one player has collected at least 250 points
 at the end of some battle. The player with the most points is the
 winner. [A mathematician would ask at this point whether anything in this
 set-up guarantees that there is a winner; a software engineer should ask
 similar questions.]
</p>

</div>
